const chaptersData = [
    {
      id: 1,
      chapterName: "Climate Change",
      videos: [
        { name: "Climate Change", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ZXhPaBRXzZxwee5_j1B4vDjCWNJ5FP1g/preview" },
      ],
      quiz: [
        {
          question: "What is climate change?",
          options: ["Natural variations in weather patterns", "A rapid increase in global temperatures", "The Earth’s cooling process", "A result of volcanic eruptions"],
          answer: "A rapid increase in global temperatures",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the greenhouse effect?",
          options: ["Heat escaping from Earth into space", "Gases trapping heat in the atmosphere", "Sunlight passing directly through the atmosphere", "A type of pollution"],
          answer: "Gases trapping heat in the atmosphere",
        },
        {
          question: "Which human activity contributes to the enhanced greenhouse effect?",
          options: ["Planting more trees", "Using renewable energy", "Burning fossil fuels", "Recycling waste"],
          answer: "Burning fossil fuels",
        },
        {
          question: "What natural process keeps Earth warm enough to support life?",
          options: ["The ozone layer", "The greenhouse effect", "The water cycle", "Wind patterns"],
          answer: "The greenhouse effect",
        },
        {
          question: "What does NASA's Climate Time Machine illustrate?",
          options: ["Changes in global temperatures", "Deforestation rates", "Industrial pollution levels", "Fossil fuel reserves"],
          answer: "Changes in global temperatures",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
        id: 2,
        chapterName: "Greenhouse Gases",
        videos: [
          { name: "Introduction", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ew2Ha3zkzbiHLhuXPP-rqukGddakbrFs/preview" },
          { name: "Sources of Greenhouse Gases", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1m_hep-nnr9lJVdPovqGvwSPBYeeYjkyr/preview" },
          { name: "The Greenhouse Effect", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ZizO2hXJDPENXvbRFnw4EiSqb_PS8Q2N/preview" },
          { name: "NASA's Role in Monitoring Greenhouse Gases", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Aw_jes2IxYx_L6O-tOw-IQPmBKplWXNg/preview" },
          { name: "Innovative Technologies in Reducing Emissions", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1tLgdo9pG9OT1tDlTLGSPY9Flr9bYdAXs/preview" },
        ],
        quiz: [
          {
            question: "What will we explore in this chapter?",
            options: ["Greenhouse gases", "Oceans", "Mountains", "Forests"],
            answer: "Greenhouse gases",
          },
          {
            question: "What is a primary source of carbon dioxide?",
            options: ["Agriculture", "Burning fossil fuels", "Refrigeration", "Landfills"],
            answer: "Burning fossil fuels",
          },
          {
            question: "What do greenhouse gases trap?",
            options: ["Water", "Heat", "Oxygen", "Light"],
            answer: "Heat",
          },
          {
            question: "What does NASA use to monitor greenhouse gases?",
            options: ["Telescopes", "Satellites", "Submarines", "Drones"],
            answer: "Satellites",
          },
          {
            question: "What does Carbon Capture and Storage (CCS) do?",
            options: ["Captures methane from livestock", "Captures carbon dioxide from industrial processes", "Captures water vapor from the atmosphere", "Captures nitrogen from the air"],
            answer: "Captures carbon dioxide from industrial processes",
          }
        ],
      },
      {
        id:3,
        chapterName:"Effects of Climate Change",
        videos:[
          { name: "A Planet Heating Up", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/10hHJdwWHBuf2cb-gj_btS1EqXFWYZguq/preview" },
          { name: "Small Change, Big Impact", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1dEDRq8mYELjaa8a-7_A3bUOqQhW0s4UJ/preview" },
          { name: "Glaciers and Ice Sheets in Peril", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1HcrVz6iPn6GYBS7wOIhIW2yKHsy8G7Vw/preview" },
          { name: "Oceans on the Rise, Coastlines in Danger", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Qz6IvNROWz-Spf9EKj4c7UYIyB1K5DDE/preview" },
          { name: "Extreme Weather Events on the Rise", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1a55W_kmj_c5xtWmEqd1VPbuskulnfKjJ/preview" },
        ],
        quiz:[
          {
            question: "What is one of the main reasons why Earth's temperature is rising rapidly?",
            options: ["Natural changes in the Earth's orbit", "Human activities such as burning fossil fuels", "Increased volcanic activity", "Solar flares"],
            answer: "Human activities such as burning fossil fuels",
          },
          {
            question: "How much has Earth's average temperature risen since the late 19th century?",
            options: ["0.5 degrees Celsius", "1.2 degrees Celsius", "2.5 degrees Celsius", "5.0 degrees Celsius"],
            answer: "1.2 degrees Celsius",
          },
          {
            question: "What is one consequence of glaciers and ice sheets melting?",
            options: ["Lowering of sea levels", "Stabilization of weather patterns", "Displacement of coastal communities", "Increased fresh water supply worldwide"],
            answer: "Displacement of coastal communities",
          },
          {
            question: "How do warmer ocean waters affect hurricanes?",
            options: ["They weaken hurricanes", "They have no effect on hurricanes", "They make hurricanes stronger and more dangerous", "They reduce the frequency of hurricanes"],
            answer: "They make hurricanes stronger and more dangerous",
          },
          {
            question: "What are some of the actions that can help mitigate climate change?",
            options: ["Building more power plants", "Continuing to use fossil fuels", "Using renewable energy and reducing pollution", "Cutting down more forests"],
            answer: "Using renewable energy and reducing pollution",
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        id:4,
        chapterName:"Human Impact",
        videos:[
            { name: "Deforestation and Its Impact", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1STdTSDVjTT9hIf4jAb0tA8jvRcS2CQ7m/preview" },
            { name: "Industrial Pollution", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1jIwIA-JcVc56L24UzAQ5sGHffAMLFxht/preview" },
            { name: "Energy Consumption and Climate Change", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1IERBGSEW_83gOfNmcCuNZQ-6z3pLPNUS/preview" },
            { name: "Everyday Actions and Climate Change", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/195NTfjA0ZnNmPtUsPVeY2YTpi7qpZ9og/preview" },
        ],
        quiz:[
          {
            question: "What is the role of forests in the environment?",
            options: ["They produce food for wildlife", "They act as carbon sinks, absorbing CO2", "They regulate rainfall patterns", "They help to warm the planet"],
            answer: "They act as carbon sinks, absorbing CO2",
          },
          {
            question: "Which gases are most commonly released by industrial pollution?",
            options: ["CO2 and methane", "Oxygen and nitrogen", "Helium and hydrogen", "Ozone and sulfur"],
            answer: "CO2 and methane",
          },
          {
            question: "Which country is mentioned as a major contributor to industrial pollution?",
            options: ["Brazil", "China", "India", "Germany"],
            answer: "China",
          },
          {
            question: "What is a major cause of greenhouse gas emissions in electricity generation?",
            options: ["Hydroelectric power", "Solar panels", "Burning coal and natural gas", "Wind turbines"],
            answer: "Burning coal and natural gas",
          },
          {
            question: "What is a major environmental issue with single-use plastics?",
            options: ["They can’t be recycled", "They release methane and ethylene as they break down", "They increase oxygen levels", "They dissolve in water easily"],
            answer: "They release methane and ethylene as they break down",
          },
        ]
      },
      {
        id:5,
        chapterName:"Solutions",
        videos:[
            { name: "Practical Steps to Save Our Planet", link: "https://drive.google.com/file/d/1pWCpVxy8p6D6nEaPGxRO6O5gy1Gk03QY/preview" },
        ],
        quiz:[
          {
            question: "What is one of the most effective ways to reduce greenhouse gas emissions?",
            options: ["Using fossil fuels", "Using renewable energy", "Increasing waste production", "Cutting down trees"],
            answer: "Using renewable energy",
          },
          {
            question: "What practice can significantly reduce the amount of waste sent to landfills?",
            options: ["Using single-use plastics", "Composting organic waste", "Burning waste", "Dumping waste in oceans"],
            answer: "Composting organic waste",
          },
          {
            question: "What role do trees play in the environment?",
            options: ["Absorbing carbon dioxide and providing oxygen", "Increasing greenhouse gases", "Reducing oxygen levels", "Producing methane"],
            answer: "Absorbing carbon dioxide and providing oxygen",
          },
          {
            question: "What is an effective method for conserving water?",
            options: ["Taking longer showers", "Fixing leaks", "Using more water for gardening", "Ignoring water-efficient appliances"],
            answer: "Fixing leaks",
          },
          {
            question: "What can Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning help with in reducing emissions?",
            options: ["Increasing energy consumption", "Optimizing energy use and predicting emission trends", "Producing more greenhouse gases", "Reducing the use of renewable energy"],
            answer: "Optimizing energy use and predicting emission trends",
          },
        ]
      }
  ];
  
  export default chaptersData;
  